made a dream the other day yeah that was
probably related to meeting you I think
there's the first time we met we be we
talked online you were I think in Dubai
or something yeah and in my dream I was
in a place like that and there was this
huge tsunami wave in the distance and
there were all of these people being you
know taken by this wave and I was with I
was just my family and we were further
away and I and the and the dream was
that we had to go up into the tower just
to save ourselves so the very fraud this
is digital digital is it tsunami yeah
it's gonna hit us Singapore because of
the skyscrapers will deal a lot better
with it you know they'll be the winners
the city states like Singapore the viral
really was planted in that's for the
nectar cracks the new superiorly to the
world are moving they're moving away
from these nation states with
territorial expansion ambitions you know
we just stopped being assessed obsessed
about this role in the West Bank and all
that because it was just the last
nation-state and finally the original
nation of Israel got their nation state
and they've perfected it that's exactly
why I sign is amidst alternate form of
nationalism but in reality I celebrate
the Palestinians for being the first
cosmopolitan somewhere did the
Palestinians live in Dubai right the
irony is that the Israelis are the last
nationalists
the Palestinians are the first
Cosmopolitan's and becoming cosmopolitan
is the future this is what Heidegger
talked about an eventually dairy dar
perfected this is what continental
philosophy started dealing with it 20
century the great part of it we'll see
what's the cause you're across from
positivism it not the harbor Marcin how
this version of it but the truly their
ideon weren't version of it is what I'm
interested in for them from our future
work and I think we need to understand
that the journey towards the Kozma Paul
the return from Jerusalem to Babylon
this time it's the interesting journey
of our time and what we have to achieve
if we get enough time to do it either
sorry infidelities going to destroy that
opportunity for us it will never get out
of the mess we're in we'll never reach
the promised land it is true then
accidents we're talking about now mm-hmm
yeah anyway I thought that the dream had
some that that was close to what you
what you're saying here is like this
there's this kind of there's a tsunami
of true though what yeah Falak sure of
this sort of coming at least it's a
memory of absolutely everything that has
happened and this is what the match are
though the woman is really good at mmm
she knows all of history she sees the
patterns she needs the mistakes being
repeated but she also sees the successes
when previous failures are learned from
and you can be successful things and
this is what the manager will tell you
because she needs to be at the very end
of the tribe when it moves to push
everybody forward because you're if
you're behind her you're dead and we're
gonna have a lot of children who refuse
to grow up today who the matchup will
have to leave behind her they cannot
join us on the exodus into the future
because I can tell you all these of
these Americans I see out there today
there's no way they can enter the world
of tomorrow they probably all end up
when they've eaten enough ambergris and
they don't die from heart failure
they're going to opioid abuse and
they're gonna die the opiate abuse ER is
the ultimate child refuses to grow
opiate abuse is the ultimate form of
infantilization that's what's a mass
epidemic in America today mm-hmm Oh
opiates the ultimate it sorry if you get
stuck without addiction
you're no use to anybody you can't even
be a crazy wisdom teacher not as an
opiate abuse or it's just impossible
because the opiates will take up your
entire mind space obsession with the
opiates will take up your entire mind
space I can tell you alcoholic parent
the problem is you're not my father
you're not my mother because the alcohol
has become your child and I cannot take
the place of the alcohol meaning I don't
have a parent hmm so I think also
there's something about tantric that's
about radical let's say acceptance of
passions and energies and that kind of
thing yeah not to exercise self-control
you'd better know yourself first right
this is like Richard Dawkins wouldn't be
pathetic a system Eevee's at least known
what he's attacking the eight fish and
requires of him that he should know what
theism is but he doesn't he doesn't
understand theology which accept accept
incredibly crucial here to understand
what theology is what's different than
philosophy also but it's it's um to
understand your own drive to understand
your own deciding what you do through
psychoanalysis
I understand drive and decide I would
even say with subtlest that we actually
have four different categories here
which are called you know this instinct
and this drive and there's desire and
there's also transcendence so but focus
on the middle to the drawing decides you
get those two and you accept the
important part of instinct mm-hm and
then you work your way towards
transcendence so then you can understand
the full spectrum oh now if you get the
full spectrum of it you also understand
how other human beings are operating
meaning for example you if you choose
sexual partners or work partners or
anybody else to deal with the team you
got around you the family you're
creating I understand what it means to
be human once you understand that he
then start the journey towards self
control and self control only is one
purpose here and that purpose is that if
I postpone the benefit all my own
talents their reward is so much richer
especially for people around me my
contributing role can do grow my
contribution becomes bigger
I've become a better hunter better
warrior better father father Bette
better mother and certainly a better
lover yeah if I could contain myself my
drives my desires but to do that I first
have to understand what they how they
work and then I can work on that and I
don't think you should look at that when
you do talk it's like any tantric sex
course that just says it that if you go
here you're gonna get fuck more it's
just like but hopefully yes but the
point here is the tantric spirituality
and the tantric spirituality is that
that will then contain and control you
turn to sexuality and that's when you
get the reward and that reward might
might be less sex but more limited
because the Pointer was to maximize the
Liberty and contain them and wake up
every morning it and be libido being
alive hmm when you're going to start
analytical work for example you discover
a certain pathology how to troll them or
something that happens you pathology
which is to miss understand how you
function you think you just basic
contained in your hand so we can use it
it can be raw material yeah you build
something from it
oh you had a trauma great at least in
your empathetic towards people who go
through that Kyle
ramaa meaning you could lead or you
could teach you could care for people
have that kind of trauma
that's crazy Weston entire life is
resources memories resources
yeah makes me think of your original
analogy at the beginning of the the the
conversation about about firming about
everything being kind of like composter
no I strongly disagree with y'all her
ease assessment you know it's just a
hearing sapiens we just like a pop book
version of Rousseau in history right is
that he he degrades farming and
agriculture and says that we were
probably happy before we got it and
we're very unhappy afterwards no there's
no argument for that at all life in the
original nomadic tribe was incredibly
tough incredibly tough so that's not
what we want to return we just want to
understand it because we're still
genetically stuck in it it is the
foundation model from which we build the
world we're still these trial beings
because we live like that for hundreds
of thousands of years and I only had
civilisation for like what are the most
5000 years America still hasn't got it
so so so to understand that is what we
need and then understand the beauty and
what we started this is all for a
students of fundamentals racism the
beauty of containing knowledge outside
of the brain and writing it down and
thereby getting wiser collectively wiser
to be able to create a larger trike to
go from tribe to climb from clan to
nation and maybe one day we'll help the
machines go from nation to go so
this whole journey is the overall
journey of humanity let's see if we
could take the last step or if this is
actually where we fail history's
continued we don't know we're gonna end
up whether we will fail at this or not
if you fail we'll fail miserably if you
succeed it will be awesome there's no
in-between so that starts with the
cultivation of the ground okay first we
were the race cattle but so does get
catalan we took the manure from the
cattle and put it on the ground we could
start to farm in farming required a
larger community each required way more
knowledge and wisdom we had in the past
them that we had to write things down
and accumulate knowledge outside of our
own brains to pass it on from one
generation to the next that is the
biggest revolution that ever happened to
us mm-hmm digital probably gonna be the
second biggest one the printing press is
a small revolution in between the G the
cultivation of the planet that could
started it and I think we need to
accomplish that fully because are we
gonna contain a plan for ten million ten
million people on it all interconnected
with each other that's gonna take so
much energy so much electricity so much
of the resources that have to be
recycled and you reuse know that and so
much of the sunlight being taken and all
that for us to be able to do that that
we need it's called through the entire
planet and that's exactly why the
overall goal of controlling and then
cultivating climate it's not to avoid
climate disaster now but to save us from
the next Ice Age mmm-hmm now if we set
the goal there
then we have the exodus of Technology
the Exodus a relationship between on a
machine we know what machine
intelligence you do to serve us and we
can answer the biggest questions of our
times that way because we finally set
the goal in the right direction we put
the goal in the right place and suddenly
everything else the aspects of the day
is just like byproducts all that overall
grand narrative that's exactly why the
grand narratives incredibly important
because all the different ideologies
were then creates to orientate ourselves
in the world will be by-product so their
overall grand narrative mm-hmm oh you're
talking about a grand narrative and then
all the other narratives that would kind
of grow from it like a tree or I'm
stopped by products there's subdivisions
of that narrative yes okay and because
we're now unified with worse priests
we're standing there seeing that okay
all the tribes are coming together and
that's not to be celebrate it's gonna be
fingers are difficult to make this work
to begin with the East in the West have
to be unified that's a sad well you and
I sitting here have a conversation so
what is it from Dulles and what is it
was or ask is what is a Buddha so what
is it on Hindu mysticism what is it from
Christianity especially on taxes but we
can pick and not pick like children pick
it like I like this or take it rather
like what is the ultimate challenge that
this specific ideology addressed in the
past that we can take from it and in the
case of Catholics or somebody's birthday
mm-hmm it's great what the Catholic
features the power of mercy hmm also the
dangers of a promising mercy to the
people who don't deserve it but still
mercy when the digital tsunami hits us
mercy is going to be the first thing we
demand massively because otherwise our
super egos are gonna take over the world
we're gonna judge ourselves and
basically call ourselves in the process
yeah that sounds very biblical again
biblical melon metaphors coming through
it sounds like the Last Judgement right
yeah if I talk to Catholics about it I
say we're really creating a third
Testament aren't we uh-huh a third
Testament the third Testaments letting
go the Father and letting go of the Sun
and
standing with parents and understand
patriarchs and matriarchs understand
what Patrick's newer mattress really
were and understand religion fully so
taking the criticism of atheism and then
throughout the atheism and then reform
the Christian message in that case and
move on to the third Testament of the
Abrahamic religion the third Testament
will be saved the Holy Ghost we wrote
about distance in system and actually
saw what she should get arrested before
we did so 2 cos 9 the the great part of
Christiana we should save as Christian
ethos it's the Holy Spirit Holy Spirit
which is the community being sacred but
for the community be sicker for God's
sake the better grow up you know it
can't be children we can't promise the
children that the divine that was the
disaster of history never ever do it
again stop the clay children are divine
they're not they're brutish little
monsters
I knew this Jewish mystic guy he was
Leonard codes teacher before he died and
he converted to all the world religions
in order to rescue the the holy spirit
you call it fear jiggle like magic
reminds me a bit of what you're saying
that the Holy Spirit just the essence of
the whole thing is is what needs to be
rescued and the nation of Israel lost
the exodus out of Egypt
it was then supported by the Empire of
the future who was the Persian Empire
the conquered Babylon and of course the
person said the Jews free they could
return to Jerusalem build the temple
Judaism and the combination which then
the Persians could use as a model
because you need the nation's would be
the Emperor for the Empire to work
that's exactly what our second book was
called the global Empire in 2003 we
pointed out already then said it is
denied but this is the ambition all our
philosophical work the global Empire is
already there it's called the Internet
the global empires gonna come back and
haunt us with its faction all that it is
monstrous tsunami of history's gonna
come all over us and it's gonna say so
since I became an empire technology why
don't you human beings also to become
Imperial where is your Imperial mindset
and Imperial mindset is way larger than
the nation it's when you go to the
neighboring nation and say why don't we
create and we thought
assess we have the same origin and we're
on the same path the problem with that
is that you have to translate the
languages to be able to do that it's
Tower of Babel all over again and maybe
then Google Translate it's the best
thing that happened with interrupt
mm-hmm again technology is there to help
us so the machine intelligence should
only have one overall goal and that
overall goal we point out and it's a
little it's the incredibly difficult
move from the intertribal to the
intertribal which is it's easier to love
your own communities a lot of your own
families easy to love your own tribe but
how do you love to learn to love the
stranger infinite demand of the stranger
some critter calls it brilliant
philosopher by the way someone's
brilliant so you take Chris's idea of
the infinite remember stranger and then
you basically do what I do then is go to
different said maybe diddle can help do
that so we go to the machines and say
can you make me love the stranger
hello blockchains hello decentralized
platforms
hello everything the hackers are doing
today the hackers are already the monks
and the nuns of the world today trying
to create sophisticated ways for people
to deal with the stranger without
killing him
and I'm not being fucking Gandhi here
okay I'm just saying this is gonna be
I'm a crazy western priest pointing
toward human beings should focus on and
I couldn't care less if they do it or
not but I am saying essentially okay if
you want to pull this trick off and save
lot human life on this planet
you know the planet doesn't care about
you are the human beings mind you should
certainly care about yourself and that
caring should mean you point yourselves
towards the infinite demand of the
stranger as the ultimate challenge of
the day that's why the Silk Road all
these things for learning now trade
routes throughout history how do we
avoid war in the past how do you move
from tribe to clan how do you move from
clan to nation
that's what Judaism is so important to
learn from but how do we not move from
nation to a global community yeah I was
just reading Jordan one of Jordan Hall's
articles and he said the next generation
is the Omega generation that was his his
theory like either the last generation
or like humanity 2.0 the last generation
or the kickoff for the next step right
and the next step here is the same cycle
the same being born the same growing up
to be an adult one day and then
hopefully being elderly wise person then
die happily with the smile on your face
and accomplish your full whole life it's
gonna stay like that for a long time we
might live longer in the future we might
start for survival dairy cow says very
explicitly system or talent he's a nasty
lie but but if you look so much howling
is actually horrible but we live longer
what do you aim for a living longer they
must be point to that and that is to
create more wisdom or universe stir your
cousin stay elderly without going
demented we can also be teachers longer
periods of which might be required of us
for the next generation because the
world is yeah I guess that's the only
point of being old isn't it to be able
to write to be a Jess yeah
[Music]
cool yeah we're getting it can you and I
now for the third parties that might
even have you know gone through all this
conversation and being part of it just
say that don't look - Andrew Sweeney not
excited about his role models oh I I
never felt like a role model - n-no I
don't think you and I want to I'm gonna
say my daughter my young daughter but in
some ways but uh yeah I live in the
gutter
yeah idling in the gutter for sure I'm
I'm the I'm defending the gutter
the gutter is needed is the people
coming out of the gutter we should
listen to you today as always when
dramatic shifts happen the history and
the paradigm shifted we're currently
going through the people in the guard
are ugly wants to get dutiful they're
gonna get it first before anybody else
because they're not full of the petit
bourgeois narcissus and it's dominating
their social media platforms today and
it's not going to survive it has no
value it adds no value no it's empty
totally empty empty it's gonna be
gruesome for these kids to discover that
[Music]
so you're like 58 years old how do you
how do you maintain such a tsunami like
energy within yourself
I don't need that
I'm embarrassed by my question actually
it's too cheesy and journalistic so
anyway that's the answer it's a very
simple very straightforward answer yeah
crazy wisdom if anything well I don't
know about the whist I'm certainly crazy
but crazy human but no but actually I
actually saw I thought I don't think
you're that crazy somehow I think that
crazy wisdom people are not crazy and
everybody else is crazy I mean you're
not crazy in the sense that your
craziness is not it's not hiding
somewhere
I think I'm crazy but I worked on my
infertility and I think it got rid of
most of it and it only pops up now and
then I can even love it and forgive it I
think the less infant Tong you can be
and the more of an adult you can be the
more you contribute the more successful
you become at being a real human being
but that's the point that's what we envy
our parents for with kids and that's we
want to be we grow up and hopefully we
succeed in that process I guess what I'm
saying
these notification of the world and
that's exactly when you and I'm Jordan
Pederson Camille Paglia
our great quadrant we're saying the same
thing the adult afect asian of society
is the most important mission today
saving the planet getting digital right
oh the other challenge we have
all follow from the desire to be adults
adult defy the world yeah start taking
let's say full spectrum eccentricity
rather than neuroticism or resentment
nerd
oh I know we're on crazy wisdom I
haven't made my bed today and I couldn't
care less but I've got an excuse for not
making the bed cuz I did something else
more that's it with you and Irv and have
a conversation man to man excuse not to
make yeah oh you got something in front
of you he can plunder and exploit oh why
don't you consider importing instead
keeping it as it is or doing something
different with it not exploited too that
makes it grow that's what rotation
foundation of cultivation which is the
foundation of Agriculture mm-hmm
exploitation is just something it's in
front of you can eat eat implication is
something is the front of you can eat it
we could also put it into the ground
back into the ground how 10 times more
than six months yes it's a flotation and
cultivation cultivation starts with
implication becomes cultivation and
that's exactly we need to do with the
entire planet we need to employed it
instead of exploit it and by learning
how to employ things we can call to
anything try reply then we can all
survive